A platform which terminates apps on its own is a pretty radical departure for
anyone like me who cut their teeth on desktop Winforms development.
If you come from a similar background you probably have
a pretty good idea of what to expect in terms of lifecycle event handles.
You start with the onCreate call back where you build and wire up your UI.
Once that's done, your activity has been created. It likely won't be a surprise
to you that there are also event handlers for when the activity becomes visible.
Which is onStart and another for when it gets focus and becomes the active
foreground app, which is onResume. That same sequence, then happens in reverse.
[SOUND] onPause indicates that the activity has lost focus, followed by
onStop when the app is no longer visible. Finally, there's an onDestroy method,
indicating the end of the app lifecycle. When your app is first launched, you'll
quickly move through these states. Create, Start, Resume, one after the other
[BLANK_AUDIO]
But within the full application lifetime, from when onCreate is first called and
till the app is finally terminated. It will move through the active lifetime and
the physical lifetime, many times. Let's look at those in a little more detail.